[
    {
        "question": "Which Native American tribe protested to halt construction of the Dakota Access Pipeline?",
        "a": "St. Regis Mohawk",
        "b": "Spirit Lake",
        "c": "Tohono O’odham",
        "d": "Tule River Yokut",
        "e": "Standing Rock Sioux",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Dakota Access Pipeline was PRIMARILY built to transport?",
        "a": "coal",
        "b": "natural gas",
        "c": "water",
        "d": "chemicals",
        "e": "oil",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which North Dakotan county did the Backwater Bridge clash over the Dakota Access Pipeline take place?",
        "a": "Emmons County",
        "b": "Carson County",
        "c": "Morton County",
        "d": "Grant County",
        "e": "Sioux County",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which danger did completion of the Dakota Access Pipeline NOT pose?",
        "a": "damage to indigenous religious sites",
        "b": "increased emissions of greenhouse gases",
        "c": "interruption of local transportation",
        "d": "disruption of local ecosystems",
        "e": "contamination of local drinking water",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ethical question did the Dakota pipeline protest raise?",
        "a": "Should natural features be granted legal rights?",
        "b": "Which groups are most affected by changing climate conditions?",
        "c": "Does economic growth justify damage to the environment?",
        "d": "Who should determine what humanity is allowed to do to the Earth?",
        "e": "Which people should be responsible for slowing climate change?",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Law enforcement argued that climate protests in the Dakota pipeline case unlawfully blocked?",
        "a": "telephone lines",
        "b": "storefront businesses",
        "c": "suburban homes",
        "d": "public roadways",
        "e": "legislative buildings",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which president ordered the construction on the Dakota Access Pipeline to continue?",
        "a": "George W. Bush",
        "b": "Bill Clinton",
        "c": "Ronald Reagan",
        "d": "Joe Biden",
        "e": "Donald Trump",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which climate activist was a leader in the movement of the Sawré Muybu Indigenous Territory?",
        "a": "Tori Tsui",
        "b": "John Paul Jose",
        "c": "Fatou Jeng",
        "d": "Dominique Palmer",
        "e": "Alessandra Korap Munduruku",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "With which company did the Sawré Muybu territory’s indigenous groups dispute?",
        "a": "Newmont Mining",
        "b": "De Beers Group",
        "c": "Anglo American",
        "d": "United Fruit",
        "e": "Guinea Company",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deforestation of Brazilian rainforests took place under the presidency of?",
        "a": "Tancredo Neves",
        "b": "Fernando Henrique Cardoso",
        "c": "Michel Temer",
        "d": "Jair Bolsonaro",
        "e": "Ernesto Geisel",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who founded the Fridays for Future climate movement?",
        "a": "Greta Thunberg",
        "b": "Rachel Carson",
        "c": "Bob Hunter",
        "d": "Alessandra Korap Munduruku",
        "e": "Irving Stowe",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "How did members of the Fridays for Future movement PRIMARILY protest governmental climate inaction?",
        "a": "blocking infrastructure",
        "b": "skipping school",
        "c": "petitioning legislators",
        "d": "advertising online",
        "e": "criticizing industrial lobbying",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "What irony of climate inaction did Greta Thunberg emphasize?",
        "a": "Less developed countries will be most affected by climate change.",
        "b": "Renewable energy is more efficient than fossil fuels.",
        "c": "Most political leaders in office will be largely unaffected by climate change in their lifetime.",
        "d": "Children are willing to act on climate while adults are not.",
        "e": "Most countries have made little contribution to global climate goals.",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which climate activist connected the equalization of climate justice to the teachings of Jesus Christ?",
        "a": "Luisa Neubauer",
        "b": "Nyombi Morris",
        "c": "Vanessa Nakate",
        "d": "Nemonte Nenquimo",
        "e": "Katherine Hayhoe",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the nationality of Vanessa Nakate?",
        "a": "Moroccan",
        "b": "Nigerian",
        "c": "Kenyan",
        "d": "Ghanaian",
        "e": "Ugandan",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    }
]
